Guide to the New-York Historical Society General Correspondence 1805-2024 (bulk, 1805-1982) NYHS-RG 2
New-York Historical Society
- Series IV. General Correspondence, 1908-1982; 117.29 Linear feet in 282 document boxes and one oversize folder
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York City-- Schools (Box 267, Folder 15)
    Concerns lectures and history programs, including "History via Movies," presented at the Society for students; exhibitions displayed in public high schools in a cooperative school-museum program arranged by the Board of Education and New York's leading cultural institutions.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York City-- Schools [Visits of Classes] ( 2 folders), 1948-1950 (Box 268, Folder 1-2)
    Concerns requests to visit the N-YHS from elementary classes throughout New York City to learn more about the city's history and the high school-Museum program held at the N-YHS.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York Folklore Society (Box 268, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York Genealogical & Biographical Society (Box 268, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York State- Historian (Box 268, Folder 4)
    Correspondent: State Historian Albert B. Corey.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York State Historical Association (Box 268, Folder 5)
    Correspondents include James Taylor Dunn (Librarian), Luis C. Jones (Director), and Mary E. Cunningham.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York State Library (Box 268, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York State- MISC. (Box 268, Folder 7)
    Concerns recommendations made to Robert Watson Pomeroy (appointed to a Joint Legislative Committee to study historical sites in New York State) of sites most worthy of study.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York State Museum (Box 268, Folder 8)
    Concerns reports from State Museum Advisory Council meetings.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York State-University of (Box 268, Folder 9)
    Concerns library reports submiited by N-YHS to the New York State Library; discussion of N-YHS serving as the depository for American Military Institute records.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York Telephone Company (Box 268, Folder 10)
    Concerns rental of private phone booth at museum and personal phone calls placed by staff. Includes a Cord Switchboard Service booklet of instructions.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. New York University (Box 268, Folder 11)
    Concerns the volunteer of elementary education students from NYU's School of Education at the N-YHS; list of publications N-YHS received from Serials Department at NYU in exchange program.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ni (Box 268, Folder 12)
    Correspondent: Robert Livingston Nicholson.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. No-Ny (Box 268, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Oa-Og (Box 268, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ogden, Beecher (Box 268, Folder 15)
    Beecher Ogden was a member of the Museum Photographers Association. Concerns his proposal for a photographic survey of the Borough of Manhattan.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Oh-Ol (Box 268, Folder 16)
    Correspondents include Alfred Van Santvoord Olcott and the Eliot O'Hara Watercolor School (Washington, D.C.).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Olds, Irving S. (Box 268, Folder 17)
    Concerns the estate of Mrs. John Jay Watson; proposed restoration of the first iron works at Saugus, Massachusetts; and plans to catalogue the N-YHS 100 years' backlog of unprocessed material (Olds served on the Plan and Scope Committee).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Om-Oz (Box 269, Folder 1)
    Correspondents include Ossining Historical Society and the Onondaga Historical Association.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Paltsits, Victor Hugo (Box 269, Folder 2)
    Concerns proposal by the American Legion to move the statue of Nathan Hale from City Hall to Halesite, Long Island.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pa (Box 269, Folder 3)
    Correspondent: John E. Parsons.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Parke-Bernet Galleries (Box 269, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pe-Pf (Box 269, Folder 5)
    Correspondent: W.P.Horton (City Historian, Peekskill, NY).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pell, Stephen H.P. (Box 269, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pennsylvania--MISC. (Box 269, Folder 7-8)
    Correspondents include the University of Pennsylvania and Pennsylvania State College.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pennsylvania Historical Society (Box 269, Folder 9)
    Correspondents include R.N.Williams (Director) and Frederic R. Kirkland (Treasurer).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Permission Slips (Box 269, Folder 10)
    Consists of slips for permission to various organizations and publications to order photographs of N-YHS items.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Peters, Harry T. (Box 269, Folder 11)
    Concerns the disposition of Harry T. Peters lithograph collection. Correspondent: Mrs. Harry T. Peters.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ph-Pl (Box 269, Folder 12)
    Concerns the acquisition of papers in connection with the building of the Synogogue on Welfare Island by the City of New York from the estate of Rosalie S. Phillips. Correspondents: The Free Library of Philadelphia, The University of Pittsburgh, and the J.P. Morgan Library.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Po (Box 269, Folder 13)
    Concerns gifts of Mr. Beekman H. Pool to the N-YHS.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Presidential Election of 1948 [Survey] (2 folders) (Box 269, Folder 14-15)
    Concerns a survey sent out by the N-YHS to approximately one hundred business Chief Executives in the United States asking for the executives to submit a statement of their opinions concerning the dominant issues of the 1948 Presidential campaign for the historical record. Includes list of names sent the survey as well as several responses.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Princeton University (Box 269, Folder 16)
    Concerns the Papers of Thomas Jefferson collection held at Princeton University Library. Correspondents include Lyman H. Butterfield and Julian P. Boyd.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pr (Box 270, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Pu-Py (Box 270, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Q (Box 270, Folder 3)
    Includes postcard sponsoring the NBC produced program, "Quiz Kids." Correspondent: Queens Borough Public Library.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ra (Box 270, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Re (Box 270, Folder 5)
    Concerns questionnaire about the N-YHS's history, collections, and building space requested from Ralph R. Reuter. Correspondent: Mrs. Henry S. Redmond.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. "Recent Accessions" Exhibition (Box 270, Folder 6)
    Concerns invitations to the exhibition on recent acquisitions during the past year.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Remington Rand Inc. (Box 270, Folder 7)
    Concerns orders for steel filing cabinets and orders to clean, oil, and adjust typewriters from Remington Rand.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Rh-Ri (Box 270, Folder 8)
    Includes advertisement for a book, American Horse-Drawn Vehicles, published by Jack D. Rittenhouse.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Roa-Rog (Box 270, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Rochester, NY (Box 270, Folder 10)
    Correspondents include the Rochester Historical Society, University of Rochester Library, and Rochester Museum of Arts and Science.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Roh-Roz (Box 270, Folder 11)
    Includes letter to Mrs. Franklin D. Roosevelt informing her of book, Entre Nous: An Intimate Portrait of Alexander J. Wall, by Lillian B. Wall (his widow) would be sent to her. Book contained chapter called, "F.D.R., The Amateur Historian," which contained previously unpublished letters of FDR. Correspondents: The Rosenbach Company and Roosevelt Memorial Association.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Romaine, Lawrence B. (Box 270, Folder 12)
    Concerns Shaker collection.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ru-Ry (Box 270, Folder 13)
    Concerns the papers of Rev. Philip Milledoeler (1775-1852), first President of Rutgers University, rescued by the N-YHS from an Oyster Bay barn.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sa (Box 270, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Saint (Box 270, Folder 15)
    Correspondents include the City Art Museum of St. Louis (Odille D. Stewart, Librarian) and the St. Louis Public Library.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sawitzky, William (Mrs.) (Box 270, Folder 16)
    Concerns photo requests for the book about Connecticut painter Reuben Moulthrop, written by Mrs. William Sawitzky from notes left by her late husband, as well as the discontinuation of the Advisory curatorship in American Art that eliminated funding to this project.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sc (Box 271, Folder 1)
    Correspondent: Charles Scribner's Sons.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sch (Box 271, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Schermerhorn, E. Gibert (Box 271, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Se (Box 271, Folder 4)
    Correspondents include Storrs H. Seeley and Harold Seton.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sha-She (Box 271, Folder 5)
    Correspondent: Donald A. Shelley.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sheean, Oliver C. (Box 271, Folder 6)
    Concerns exhibition of Oliver Clement Sheean Collection of bookplates.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Shi-Shu (Box 271, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Si-Sl (Box 271, Folder 8)
    Concerns attendance records for years 1946-1949 for New York City museums and Institutions. Correspondents include Theodore Sizer and Mrs. Roswell Skeel, Jr.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sm (Box 271, Folder 9)
    Concerns the bequest of Mrs. Bessie Clarkson Smedberg; report on the Parish Church of Scrooby, Notts, St. Wilfrids (England).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sn-So (Box 271, Folder 10)
    Concerns the Society of Architectural Historians informal report on some of the Society's activities for 1948.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sons of the Revolution (Box 271, Folder 11)
    Concerns Washington's Birthday annual celebration in Carnegie Hall on February 22, 1949.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sp-Sq (Box 271, Folder 12)
    Correspondents include Springfield Art Museum (Missouri) and the Frank Squier Paper Company.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sta (Box 271, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ste (Box 271, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Stevens, B.F. & Brown, Ltd. (Box 271, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sti-Sto-Sty (Box 272, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Streeter, Thomas W. (2 folders) (Box 272, Folder 2-3)
    Concerns Streeter's role as Treasurer of the N-YHS. Includes requests for signatures for checks, payroll, real estate property, bonds, museum budget reports, and other matters.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Su (Box 272, Folder 4)
    Correspondent: Sunnyside Restoration (Alice M. Runyon).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Sw-Sy, 1947-1949 (Box 272, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ta-Te (Box 272, Folder 6)
    Concerns lecture on the exhibition of photographs by Leonard Dakin, "Social Life in the 1880s," given by Mrs. Arthur I. Taft (daughter of Dakin) at the Albright Art Gallery.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Th (Box 272, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ti (Box 272, Folder 8)
    Correspondent: Title Guarantee and Trust Company
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. To-Tr (Box 272, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Tu-Ty (Box 272, Folder 10)
    Correspondent: Charles E. Tuttle Company.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. U (Box 272, Folder 11)
    Correspondent: Union College.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. U.S.A.-- Library of Congress (Box 272, Folder 12)
    Correspondents include W.S. Jenkins (Director, State Records Microfilm Project), and Frederick R. Goff (Chief, Rare Books Division).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. U.S.A.-- MISC. (Box 273, Folder 1)
    Correspondents include National Park Service, Congress of the United States, and the West Point Military Academy.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Navy Department/Naval Academy (Box 273, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. United States Post Office (Box 273, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. U.S.A.-- Smithsonian Institution (Box 273, Folder 4)
    Concerns the request by the Bureau of America Society for the N-YHS to microfilm the copy of George S. Conover's "Kanadasaga and Geneva," owned by the Ontario Historical Society.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. U.S.A.-- Treasury Department (Box 273, Folder 5)
    Concerns bank policies and savings bonds for employees and the inflation following World War II.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Va-Val (Box 273, Folder 6)
    Correspondent: The Valentine Museum (Richmond, VA).
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Vail, R.W.G., 1948-1950 (Box 273, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Van-Vaz, 1948-1951. (Box 273, Folder 8)
    Concerns death of Kiliaen Van Rensselaer and list of his gifts to the Society.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Ve (Box 273, Folder 9)
    Correspondent: Vermont Historical Society,
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Vi (Box 273, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Virginia--MISC (Box 273, Folder 11)
    Correspondents include the Virginia Historical Society and University of Virginia.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Vo-Vu (Box 273, Folder 12)
    Correspondent: Robert C. Vose Galleries.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Von Hagan, Victor W. (Box 273, Folder 13)
    Concerns publication of Frederick Catherwood Architect, by Von Hagan, and a series of exhibitions on Catherwood held at Columbia University and other institutions.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wa-Wak (Box 273, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wal (Box 273, Folder 15)
    Concerns the piblication of Entre Nous by Mrs. Alexander Wall. Correspondent: Paul Q.W.Wallace.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wan-Waz (Box 273, Folder 16)
    Concerns the permanent placing of John Jay Watson's portrait in the Art Gallery of the Society. Correspondent: Wayne County Historical Society.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wea-Wek (Box 273, Folder 17)
    Correspondent: Frank Weitenkampf.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Weekes Brothers--Arthur Sutherland (Box 274, Folder 1)
    Correspondence with Joseph J. Smith concerns sales of properties owned by the N-YHS, mortgage certificates, and the passing of Arthur Sutherland.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wel-Wez (Box 274, Folder 2)
    Correspondents include Katherine Wellenkamp and the Western Range Cattle Industry Study.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Westervelt, Leonidas (Box 274, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wh (Box 274, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Whitlock's (Box 274, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wia-Wik (Box 274, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wickes, Forsyth (Box 274, Folder 7)
    Concerns a speech given by Forsyth Wickes on Verrazano and his voyage in La Dauphine.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wil (2 folders) (Box 274, Folder 8-9)
    Correspondents include Willoughbys, William and Mary Quarterly (Margaret Kinard, Assistant Editor), and the Willman Paper Company.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wills, Louis C. (Box 274, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wilmerding, Lucius (Box 274, Folder 11)
    Concerns Lucius Wilmerding's obituary and funeral arrangements.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wim-Wiz (Box 274, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wisconsin [State Historical Society] (Box 274, Folder 13)
    Correspondent: Clifford Lord, Director.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Withey, Fred S. (Box 274, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Woa-Woz (Box 274, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Wr-Wy (Box 274, Folder 16)
    Concerns a contest "Pennsylvania Dutch versus Pennsylvania German" held by the Wyomissing Institute of Fine Arts (Reading, PA), to decide the preferred term to be used.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. X-Y (Box 274, Folder 17)
    Correspondent: Young Men's Christian Association.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Yale University (Box 274, Folder 18)
    Correspondent: Theodore Sizer.
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Z (Box 274, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence 1948-1949. Zabriskie, George A. (2 folders) (Box 274, Folder 20-21)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Addressograph (Box 275, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Aa-Ad (Box 275, Folder 2)
    Concerns an estimate for suitable permanent outdoor bronze cases to contain removable signs for advertising purposes (large displays attracted more people into the building).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Ae-Am (Box 275, Folder 3)
    Includes brochure for Air Music, Inc. Planned Music for background music. Correspondents include Albany Institute of History and Art.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. American Antiquarian Society (2 folders) (Box 275, Folder 4-5)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. American A- American F (Box 275, Folder 6)
    Correspondent: American Association for State and Local History.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. American G- American K (2 folders) (Box 275, Folder 7-8)
    Correspondents: American Jewish Archives and the America Jewish Historical Society.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. American L- American Z (2 folders) (Box 275, Folder 9-10)
    Correspondents include the American Red Cross, American Library Association, American Museum of Natural History, and the American Scenic and Historic Preservation Society.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. An-Aq (Box 275, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Ar-Az (Box 275, Folder 12)
    Concerns the building of the Margaret Mitchell library in Georgia. Correspondent: Atlanta Historical Society.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Baa-Bai (Box 275, Folder 13)
    Correspondent: Old Museum Village of Smith's Cove (includes schedule of activities).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bak-Ban (Box 275, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bank of New York (Box 275, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bar-Baz (2 folders) (Box 276, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bea-Bem (Box 276, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Beekman, Fenwick/Beekman Family Association (Box 276, Folder 4)
    Concerns the Beekman Family Collection portraits, Ancestal Portrait of the Beekman family.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Ben-Bez (Box 276, Folder 5)
    Correspondent: Bennett Book Studios.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. BI-BL (Box 276, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bibliographical Society of America (Box 276, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bo (2 folders) (Box 276, Folder 8-9)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bra-Bri (Box 276, Folder 10)
    Correspondents include Otis Treat Bradley and The British Museum.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bro (Box 276, Folder 11)
    Concerns inscriptions (in Italian and English) on the reconditioned Verrazano monument which sheds lights on France's part in the discovery of the New York harbor; Civil War round table Luncheon (guest list).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Brooklyn Museum (Box 276, Folder 12)
    Correspondent: Charles Nagel (Director).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. John Carter Brown Library (Box 276, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bru-Bun (Box 276, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Bur-By (Box 277, Folder 1)
    Correspondent: John Kenneth Byard (Silvermine antique dealer).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Caa-Cal (Box 277, Folder 2)
    Concerns books sent to the Cadmus Book Shop by the N-YHS.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cam-Car ( 2 folders) (Box 277, Folder 3-4)
    Concerns vocational counseling brochure for women published by Careers for Women. Correspondents include National Museum of Canada and the Public Archives of Canada.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cas-Ce (Box 277, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Chicago (Box 277, Folder 6)
    Concerns the beneficiaries (including N-YHS) from the estate of J. Insley Blair. Correspondents include Chicago Historical Society (H. Maxson Holloway).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cha-Chm (Box 277, Folder 7)
    Concerns the acquisition of Greenwich Village photographs from Arthur D. Chapman.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cho-Ci (Box 277, Folder 8)
    Correspondent: The Civil War Round Table.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cla-Clm (Box 277, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Clements Library (University of Michigan) (Box 277, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Coa-Col (Box 277, Folder 11)
    Consists of background literature for the Color Slides Cooperative (Princeton, NJ).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Colonial Williamsburg (Box 277, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Columbia University (Box 277, Folder 13)
    Concerns History course taught by R.W.G. Vail for 1952-1953 school year and the cooperation between Columbia and the N-YHS on an Oral History Project.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Com-Con (Box 277, Folder 14)
    Correspondents include James Brewster (State Librarian, Connecticut State Library) and the Connecticut Historical Society (Thompson R. Harlow, Director).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Coo-Cor (Box 277, Folder 15)
    Correspondents include Cornell University, Cooper Union Library, and Corning Glass Works.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Corcoran Gallery of Art (Box 277, Folder 16)
    Concerns loan of materials from N-YHS for the exhibition, American Processional, and the Sesquicentennial Exhibition.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cos-Coz (Box 278, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cr (Box 278, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cu-Cz (Box 278, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Cuyler, T. Cruger (Box 278, Folder 4)
    Concerns the death of Colonel T. Cruger Cuyler.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Da-Dav (Box 278, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Dav-Day (Box 278, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. De (2 folders) (Box 278, Folder 7-8)
    Correspondent: The Denver Art Museum.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Delafield, John Ross (Box 278, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Delaware (Box 278, Folder 10)
    Correspondent: The Historical Society of Delaware.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Detroit (Box 278, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Di (Box 278, Folder 12)
    Concerns the publication of Jarvis manuscript by Harold E. Dickson.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Do (Box 278, Folder 13)
    Exchanges with Paul H. Dowling discuss the possible establishment of a museum dedicated to horse-drawn transportation.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Dr-Dz, 1949-1951 (Box 278, Folder 14)
    Concerns the life and work of French engineer Marc Isambard Brunel (1769-1849).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Dunlap, Charles E. (Box 278, Folder 15)
    Concerns the securing of miniatures and other items at the Norvin H. Green sale for the N-YHS collections.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. DuPont (Box 278, Folder 16)
    Correspondents include Joseph Downs (Curator, Henry Francis Du Pont Winterthur Museum).
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Ea-Ec (Box 278, Folder 17)
    Concerns photographer Richard Hoe Lawrence, member of the old New York Camera Club, an organization of amateur photographers in the 1870-1880s. Correspondent: George Eastman House.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Ed-Ek (Box 278, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. El-Em (Box 278, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. En-Ez (Box 278, Folder 20)
    Concerns exhibition commemorating the 125th anniversary of the completion of the Erie Canal. Correspondent: Erie Railroad Company.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fa (Box 279, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fe (Box 279, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fi (Box 279, Folder 3)
    Correspondent: Stuyvesant Fish.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fl (Box 279, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fo (Box 279, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Foreign ( 2 folders) (Box 279, Folder 6-7)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fr (2 folders) (Box 279, Folder 8-9)
    Correspondent: The French Folklore Society.
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Frick Art Reference Library (Box 279, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence 1950-1951. Fu (Box 279, Folder 11)